Nikhil Chukka

Fairfax, Virginia | 571-376-1735 | nikhilchukka335@qmail.com | @Portfolio | @LinkedIn | @GitHub

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Versatile developer with a Master's in Computer Science, distinguished for collaborative skills and a track record of independently delivering impactful results. Ample experience in software development, delivering well-documented, tested, and operable code. Efficient in collaborating and communicating new ideas and opinions.

AWARDS AND CERTIFICATIONS

Salesforce Certified Platform App Builder | Accenture Salesforce Certified Administrator | Accenture Key Performer Award | Accenture Salesforce Certified Platform Developer I | Accenture

June 2022 April 2022 December 2021 November 2021

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: C/C++, Java, Python, SQL (MS-SQL, MySQL), JavaScript, HTML, XML, JSON, CSS

Frameworks: Bootstrap, JQuery, Numpy, Pandas, Matplotlib, Hadoop, Mapreduce, Apache Pig, Kafka

Tools: Git, Jenkins, Salesforce CRM, Tableau, SonarCube, VS Code, Selenium

Others: Data Modeling, Agile (Scrum/Kanban), SOLID, Design Patterns, Debugging, Root Cause Analysis

EXPERIENCE

Application Development Analyst | Accenture

October 2020 – November 2022

- Actively participated in the development of a Salesforce Cloud application, leveraging continuous integration and continuous deployment (CI/CD) methodologies with tools such as Bitbucket (Git), Jenkins, and SonarQube to enhance development efficiency and code quality.
- Implemented Salesforce automation solutions including Workflow Rules, Process Builders, and Flows, achieving a 30 percentage reduction in manual effort by automating repetitive tasks and streamlining business processes.
- Designed and developed comprehensive dashboards using Einstein Analytics, providing key performance indicators (KPIs)
 and valuable insights that supported data-driven decision-making and strategic planning.

Salesforce Administrator Intern | Coanizant Technologies

May 2019 – July 2019

- Designed and developed an application called 'DreamHouse' which leverages Salesforce's robust data management capabilities to store and organize extensive property listings, enabling dynamic search functionality with filters.
- Utilized Salesforce Lightning Components to create a highly interactive and user-friendly interface, allowing for seamless navigation and an engaging experience for prospective homebuyers.
- Integrated Salesforce CRM functionalities to track user interactions, inquiries, and preferences, facilitating personalized communication and follow-ups with potential buyers through automated email campaigns and notifications.

EDUCATION

George Mason University
Jawaharlal Technological University

PROJECTS

Project 1 | Custom Password generator using HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Spring 2024

- Designed the application's layout and visual elements using HTML and CSS, focusing on a minimalist and user-friendly design aesthetic.
- Implemented the password generation logic in JavaScript, ensuring robust and secure random password creation based on user preferences.
- Conducted thorough testing across different browsers and devices to ensure functionality and responsiveness, optimizing the code for performance and user experience.

Project 2 | Portfolio using HTML, CSS and JavaScript

Fall 2023

- Spearheaded the entire front-end development process, from designing the UI/UX to coding the website using HTML, CSS, and JavaScript.
- Implemented a responsive navigation menu, dynamic content sections, interactive UI elements, and integrated social media profiles for a comprehensive digital profile.
- Curated and composed all website content, including personal information, professional experience, showcased projects, and contact details.

Project 3 | Classifying Fake News Articles Using ML Techniques

April 2020

- A Machine Learning project using Python coded in Google Colab. A novel fake news detector that uses quoted attribution in a Bayesian machine learning system as a key feature to estimate the likelihood that a news article is fake. Performance analysis is done between Multinomial Naive Bayes classifier, Decision tree classifier and Logistic Regression.

PUBLICATIONS

Publication 1	Classifying Fake News Articles Using Machine Learning Techniques	Sep 2021
	Analysis of Various Machine Learning Classification Algorithms for COVID-19 Face Mask Identification	Aug 2021
Publication 3	Hadoop Based Generic Template for Performing Sentiment Analysis Using Apache PIG	July 2021